[Music]
so can a hardened atheist believe that's
a hard question look many atheists are
iron-willed when it comes to this
subject
they're like iron unwilling to break or
bend or you might be an agnostic saying
look we can't really know if God exists
and listen I get it I used to be
skeptical of religion see I reason that
if there really was a true God a true
religion then why were there so many
religions in the first place right in
fact I believe that people were what
they were not because of conviction but
because they were either brought up that
way or became whatever the dominant
religion of that society was so if you
were born in a Muslim country you'd
probably be Muslim if you were born in a
Christian country you'd probably be
Christian another argument that didn't
really sit well with me was the moral
argument when people said to me listen I
became what I became because it made me
a better person
I'd ask well what about all the other
religions that have made other people
better people I know totally secular
people who became better people without
religion and I know some secular people
who are more moral than religious people
so the moral argument didn't sit well
with me didn't carry much weight with me
and if I was gonna believe that there
really was a true God a true religion
I'd need to have evidence that was
incontrovertible now let me ask you a
question let's say that you and I just
met and I asked you to trust me with
your future
I wanted you to trust every word I said
to you you probably say this guy's crazy
why would I do that
but I proceeded to tell you that I'm
going to foretell 20 things that were
going to happen to you in the next 24
hours starting tomorrow morning on your
way to work
you're gonna barely miss hitting a dog
as you're driving to work when you get
to work you're gonna see four doves at
your front door when you see those four
doves it will immediately begin to rain
but only for three minutes
when the rain stops you're gonna see a
rainbow I continue to list up these 20
things that are gonna happen and now
you're thinking this guy is crazy he's
really crazy you go on your way and you
forget this whole encounter the next
morning you get up and on your way to
work you almost hit a dog when you get
to work what do you see at your front
door four doves as soon as you see those
four doves it begins to rain but it
rains only for three minutes why do you
know that because you have your watch on
and you're looking because you're in
disbelief as soon as it stops raining
you see the rainbow now let me ask you a
question
are you beginning to think that
everything I said to you and everything
else that I said was going to happen was
going to be accurate are you beginning
the thing that maybe you should trust me
with your future if I could accurately
foretell the future it would be silly of
you not to listen to me right okay I
can't foretell the future but let me ask
you another question
if I could show you that the Bible
accurately foretold not 24 hours but
thousands of years of history in advance
history that could be verified history
down to our very day would you and
iron-willed
atheist belief let me have just a few
more moments of that iron will so the
book of daniel was written in the sixth
century BC some skeptics placed the book
closer to the second century BC but
whether you believe the book was written
in the 6th century or the 2nd century
doesn't really matter because either way
the book predicted over 2,000 years of
history accurately let me explain seen
the second chapter of daniel the king of
babylon has a dream in it he sees an
image of a man whose head is of gold his
chest and arms of silver his belly and
his eyes are made of brass his legs of
iron and the toes of iron and clay he
then sees a stone coming from heaven
which hits the image on the feet of iron
and clay the King has no idea what the
dream means but the prophet Daniel
explains to him that these symbols
represent kingdoms the head of gold
Daniel tells him is a symbol of the
kingdom of Babylon his kingdom
Daniel proceeds to tell him that his
kingdom would fall to another kingdom of
silver and that one would eventually
fall to a third Kingdom represented by
the brass and then a fourth kingdom
would finally rule made of iron history
tells us that the kingdom that overthrew
Babylon was the medo-persian empire
medo-persia fell to Greece and Greece
fell to Rome remember Daniel is writing
in the sixth century BCE
that's almost 1000 years of history this
is why I skeptics see two places the
Book of Daniel in the 2nd century BC
because how else would Daniel have
accurately been able to predict the rise
and fall of these four nations unless he
was riding after it already happened but
let's grant for a moment that the book
was written in the time of the early
Roman Empire what comes next is
absolutely amazing you see Daniel didn't
say that Rome would be overthrown by a
fifth kingdom instead he said this
fourth kingdom would be broken down into
smaller kingdoms and this is exactly
what happened to Rome by 476 ad Rome had
fallen and in its place smaller kingdoms
had risen France Germany England Spain
in other words modern-day Europe this
prophecy then covers Europe as we know
it today guys that's between 2000 to
2600 years of history depending on what
date you choose to accept the Book of
Daniel was written but that's not where
the story ends the toes of iron and clay
have special significance
Daniel the Prophet explained that the
iron and clay would not mix together
they would be at odds if you will listen
carefully iron in the Bible is a symbol
of stubbornness a refusal to hear the
word of God for example Jeremiah 628
says this they are all grievious revolt
errs walking with slanders they are
brass and iron they are all corrupters
and Isaiah 48 verse 4 says this because
I knew that thou art obstinate and thy
neck is an iron sinew and thy brow brass
in other words these verses show that
iron and brass symbolized rebellion
against God listen each one of these
kingdoms starting with Babylon grew
harder and more obstinate against God
with time that's why the medals go from
gold to silver to brass iron the iron
kingdom of Rome is the kingdom that
crucified Christ and persecuted the
early Christian church of all these four
ancient kingdoms ancient Rome was the
most obstinate against God the European
nations that came out of Rome were also
represented by iron but remember that
there was another element another
kingdom among these secular nations that
was the clay kingdom clay in the Bible
is used as a symbol of religious people
as is 64 verse 8 says but now O Lord
thou art our Father we are the clay and
thou the Potter and we are the work of
our hands so a clay kingdom would
symbolize a kingdom opposite of iron a
kingdom that claims to believe in the
Heavenly Father and true the history
during the Middle Ages there was a power
struggle between the kings of Europe and
the Church of Europe for a long time the
church ruled over the states clay ruled
over iron but with an iron fist the
hypocrisy of the clay of the church
would eventually lead to a revolt that
would burst open during the French
Revolution
and it is there where atheism responded
with a vengeance a reign of terror in
response to over a thousand years of
abuse from the church since then the
battle between iron and clay between
church and state can vividly be seen in
our society just as the Bible predicted
now listen the last thing to happen in
this dream was a stone coming from
heaven to destroy the iron and the clay
the stone Daniel tells us was a symbol
of the second coming of Jesus so wait a
minute
Jesus destroys the clay with the iron
yes you see in this vision the clay is
no better than the iron why because the
clay was to represent the character of
Jesus but instead through their actions
during the Dark Ages and yes even today
they are turning more and more people
into iron while claiming to be clay they
act more like iron by the hypocritical
acts and attitudes of men who profess to
be followers of Christ
many people are turned away from Christ
in this sense hypocritical clay helped
to produce the iron we see today and the
Bible foretold this no other holy book
no other religion has prophecy of this
calibre look if I told you 20 things
were going to happen in 90
came to pass as I say what would be the
odds of the 20th thing would most
certainly happen the Bible tells us that
the stone coming from heaven represents
the coming of Christ
if everything the Bible said would
happen before this has accurately come
to pass then what are the odds that
Jesus will return if your iron is not
too late for you to believe and if
you're a hypocritical clay it's not too
late for you to be change listen can an
iron world atheist believe
[Music]